<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homeworks on Programming tools for data science</title>
    <link>/homeworks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homeworks on Programming tools for data science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 17:26:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/homeworks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>/homeworks/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 17:10:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/homeworks/schedule/</guid>
      <description>gantt dateFormat YYYY-MM-DD title Schedule for the homeworks section Practicals homework 0 :active, des1, 2018-09-18, 1d homework 1 :active, des2, 2018-09-25, 2018-10-02 homework 2 :active, des3, 2018-10-16, 2018-10-23 homework 3 :active, des4, 2018-10-30, 2018-11-06 homework 4 :active, des5, 2018-11-13, 2018-11-20 section Deadlines homework 1 :crit, 2018-10-15, 1d homework 2 :crit, 2018-11-05, 1d homework 3 :crit, 2018-11-19, 1d homework 4 :crit, 2018-12-03, 1d  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>homework #0</title>
      <link>/homeworks/hw0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 16:40:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/homeworks/hw0/</guid>
      <description>Homework generously provided by the Data Science in Business Analytics class.
This homework is optional and is not graded.
 In this optional tutorial you will get an overview of the basic programming concepts in R and main data types. Just enough to get you up and running essential R code. However, for true &amp;ldquo;beginners&amp;rdquo;, we highly recommend going through Advanced R - Chapter &amp;lsquo;Foundations&amp;rsquo; from which the content of this assignment is mainly (mostly) inspired by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>homework #1</title>
      <link>/homeworks/hw1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 16:40:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/homeworks/hw1/</guid>
      <description>Deadline: 2018-10-15 at 4pm
To submit your work, add samorso and irudnyts as collaborators to your private GitHub repo.
We will grade only the latest files prior to the deadline. Any ulterior modifications are pointless.
 The objectives of this homework assignment are the followings:
 Build your own RMarkdown document.
 Master different aspects of RMarkdown syntax.
 Become familiar with GitHub as a collaborative tool.  To begin with, create a (preferably private) GitHub repository for your group, and name it ptds2018hw1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>