<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorials on Programming tools for data science</title>
    <link>/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorials on Programming tools for data science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:17:38 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R Coding Style Guide</title>
      <link>/tutorials/style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:18:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/style/</guid>
      <description>Good coding style is like using correct punctuation. You can manage without it, but it sure makes things easier to read.  Hadley Wickham 
 Introduction A language is a tool that allows human beings to interact and communicate with each other. The clearer we express ourselves, the better an idea is transferred from our mind to the other. The same applies to programming languages: concise, clear and consistent codes are easier to read and/or edit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-oriented workflow</title>
      <link>/tutorials/workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:19:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/workflow/</guid>
      <description>It’s like agreeing that we will all drive on the left or the right. A hallmark of civilization is following conventions that constrain your behavior a little, in the name of public safety.  Jenny Bryan 
 Introduction In this tutorial we will learn key aspects of making a good research project:
 reproducible portable self-contained  In data science context, reproducibility means that the whole analysis can be recreated (or repeated) from the fresh start and raw data and get exactly the same results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>